<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>obgyn on PerceptronMD</title>
    <link>/tags/obgyn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in obgyn on PerceptronMD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Robert Chen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 20:57:59 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/obgyn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ectopic Pregnancy</title>
      <link>/posts/ectopic-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 20:57:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ectopic-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>Encounter A 36-year-old G1P0010 woman presents to the office with onset of light vaginal bleeding, which she feels is not her menstrual period, and mild right lower quadrant pain, which she rates as 2/10. The pain is intermittent and crampy, and is not associated with urination. There is no nausea or vomiting. The patient’s last bowel movement was yesterday and was normal in consistency without blood or black color. Her past medical history is notable for no allergies, no medications, and two hospitalizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypertension in Pregnancy</title>
      <link>/posts/hypertension-in-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 20:35:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hypertension-in-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>Encounter A 22-year-old G1P0 currently at 38 0/7 weeks presents for her routine prenatal visit. She has had an uncomplicated pregnancy up to this point, with the exception of a late onset of prenatal care and obesity (BMI of 35 kg/m2). She reports that during the past week, she has noted some swelling of her hands and feet. She also has been feeling a bit more fatigued and has had a headache on and off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes Mellitus in Pregnancy</title>
      <link>/posts/diabetes-mellitus-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 19:58:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/diabetes-mellitus-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>Encounter 1 37yo Hispanic woman G2P1001 at 10w3d comes today for her new OB visit. She is overall doing well but has concerns from her previous pregnancy. Her first pregnancy was complicated by a diagnosis of gestational diabetes mellitus. She worries about this diagnosis for this pregnancy. She wonders how common is GDM and why she had it in her previous pregnancy. How do you counsel her and what are your next steps?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premature Rupture of Membranes</title>
      <link>/posts/premature-rupture-membranes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 18:45:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/premature-rupture-membranes/</guid>
      <description>Motivating Example A 26-year-old G2P0101 woman who is 12 weeks pregnant, presents to your prenatal clinic for a new patient visit. Her history is significant vaginal delivery 12 months ago. Beginning at 24 weeks in her previous pregnancy, the patient presented numerous times to Labor and Delivery reporting contractions, and she was sent home each time with a diagnosis of “Braxton-Hicks contractions.” She eventually presented at 28-weeks gestation and was diagnosed with preterm labor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
